Guide to the Lewis L. Delafield, Eugene D. Hawkins and Affiliated Attorneys Records circa 1856-1921 (bulk, 1880s-1910) MS 157
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Boxes labeled D-L (Delafield-Longfellow), 1880s-1914 (bulk 1890s-1908)
  - Subseries I.B. Printed Papers, 1890-1909
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, circa 1895-1899 (Offsite-box 28)
      Packet #10) Austin C. Chase v. City of Syracuse, James K. McGuire (mayor), and Elbert F. Allen (treasurer); Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 4th Dept; brief for appellants; 1899.
      Packet #11) Dorothea R. Christ v. Third Avenue Railroad Company; Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept; 2 documents: papers on appeal from order granting injunction pendente lite (1896), and brief for appellant (1897). Also, Catharine L. Beekman v. Third Avenue Railroad Company, Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept; 2 documents: papers on appeal from order granting injunction pendente lite (1896), and brief for appellant (1897).
      Packet #12) Charles E. Pearsall v. Harriet F. Van Zandt; New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 2nd Dept, Westchester County; brief for respondent, 1896.
      Packet #13) John Porter Shannon v. Margaret C. Pentz et al; New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept; 3 documents: points for infant defendants and respondents Porter C. Shannon and Gertrude M. Shannon; brief on behalf of the plaintiff and respondent; papers on appeal from interlocutory judgment; ca. 1895.
      Packet #14) Re: Jamaica Town Bonds. In the matter of $450,000, 5% Gold Road Bonds of the Town of Jamaica, Queens, NY, 1898.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 15, 16, 17, 18, circa 1896-1899 (Offsite-box 28)
      Packet #15) Bernard H. Roozen v. James E. Clonin as assignee for benefit of the creditors of Herman Dreyer; Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 2nd Dept; 2 documents: statement/brief for appellant; case on appeal; 1896-97.
      Packet #16) Samuel F. Myers v. Marcus A. Myers and Simon Blumauer, in matter of application of Joseph Fahys, Henry F. Cook and George E. Fahys doing business as firm of Joseph Fahys & Co., etc.; Supreme Court, New York County; brief in support of motion for permission to levy on goods in the hands of the receiver, 1896. Also Samuel F. Myers v. Marcus A. Myers and Simon Blumauer, in matter of application of the New York Life Insurance and Trust Company for an order directing Lewis Clark, Jr, receiver of the property of S.F. Myers & Co. to deliver property to New York Life.
      Packet #17) J. Walter Thompson v. Henry E. Child re: recovery of payment for advertising in Life magazine done by Thompson as agent for Child; Supreme Court, New York County; 4 documents: case on appeal, brief for appellant, statement of facts, etc.; 1898.
      Packet #18) William Ellson v. Edwin A. Hance, impleaded with Daniel L. Risley; Supreme Court, Appellate Division 1st Dept; 3 documents: papers on appeal from order denying motion to vacate order of arrest as to appellant Edwin A. Hance; brief for respondent, appellant's brief; 1899.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 19, 20, 21, circa 1895-1898 (Offsite-box 28)
      Packets #19 and 20) Matter of application of Winthrop E. Scarritt for a peremptory writ of mandamus to compel the payment by the City of New York of overdue coupons on 140 bonds issued by the Town of Southfield (Richmond County); Supreme Court, New York County; order to show cause and affidavits; 1898.
      Packet #21) Brooklyn Elevated Railroad Company v. John Flynn re: acquiring title to real estate or right of way on Myrtle Ave, Brooklyn, Kings County; Court of Appeals, New York State; appeal book and two related documents; ca. 1895.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 35, 39, circa 1897-1898. (Offsite-box 29)
      Packet #35) Leopold Weil v. Joseph Bermel (supervisor of Newtown, Queens), George W. Morton (town clerk), supervisors of Queens County, and others re: disposition of town bonds; several related documents; ca. 1897.
      Packet #39) Application of Luther D. Garrett for a peremptory writ of mandamus to compel the payment by the City of New York of overdue coupons on 80 bonds issued by the Town of Westfield (Richmond County); Supreme Court, New York County; 1898.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 40, 45, 1890-1892, circa 1900 (Offsite-box 29)
      Packet #40) James C.E. D'Esterre v. City of New York and Bird S. Coler (comptroller) re: Gravesend bonds (Kings County); U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals for 2nd District; 1900.
      Packet #45) Frederick P. Delafield, Benjamin A. Gould, and Frederick W. Longfellow (as the firm) v. City of Syracuse re: recovery of fees for services rendered; Supreme Court, Onondaga County; brief and argument for the plaintiff; ca. 1900.
      The original box also held two booklets with no obvious packet number. One booklet appears to be stubs from a checkbook, 1890-1892, possibly Lewis L. Delafield's based on the entries. The second booklet are stubs either from a checkbook or a receipts book, April-December 1892.
    - D & L Print Matter Packet 46, circa 1899-1904 (Offsite-box 29)
      Arthur W. Hart v. L.D. Garrett Company; Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; case on appeal printed matter. Also has typescripts of related material. Re: dispute over amount owed to Hart by Garrett because of a sale of the Orient Insurance Company to the London & Lancashire Fire Insurance Company, ca. 1903-04. Includes a copy of the "Insurance Reference Book" published by L.D. Garrett Company, Reporting Dept., 1899.
    - D & L Print Matter Packet 47, circa 1903 (Offsite-box 30)
      Sarah May Le Brantz v. William G. Conklin (executor of estate of Sarah Ann Waters, deceased 4/4/1902), American Female Guardian Society and Home for the Friendless of New York City, Guild for the Crippled Children of the Poor of New York City, et al, Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; papers on appeal; re: will/esate dispute; July 1903.
    - D & L Print Matter Packet 49, 1893-1901 (Offsite-box 30)
      The content are not printed papers, but financial records. It is not entirely clear but these seem to be records of architects Abner J. Haydel and Augustus D. Shepard, Jr. All of the volumes are initialed on the inside cover "WHM Dec 2 '02." The volumes are: 1) Cash record from May 1893-February 1901. 2) Account book ca. 1894-1901. 3) Day book, November 1894-April 1901 (there are some Haydel/Shepard invoices in this book). 4) 5 checkbooks May 1893-June 1901.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 50, 51, 52, 59, circa 1896-1898 (Offsite-box 31)
      Packets #50 and 51) Joshua L. Baily, Frederic L. Baily, Albert L. Baily, and James Talcott v. Lewis M. Hornthal, Albert Weis and Robert Weis. Also Cornelius N. Bliss et al v. Hornthal and the Weises; and Clement A. Auffmordt et al v. Hornthal and the Weises; and Thomas A. Whicher, Louis E. Whicher and John B. Sexton v. Hornthal and the Weises; re: business dispute over distribution of partnership assets; Supreme Court, New York County,and later Appeals Court and Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; several documents; ca. 1896-98.
      Packet #52) Multiple copies of booklet "Investment of Trust Funds in the New England and Middle Atlantic States. Compliments of Kountze Brothers, Bankers, New York," 1902. Written by Delafield & Longfellow.
      Packet #59) Blank agreement forms for use between The Warrenton Gun Club and tenants of its land in North Carolina, ca. 1900.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 53, 54, 58, 60, circa 1900-1906 (Offsite-box 32)
      Packet #53) "Deposit agreement. The Cincinnati Securities Company with Commercial Trust Company of New Jersey; relating to common stock of the Union Gas and Electric Company." October 1, 1906.
      Packet #54) "Lease. The Cincinnati Gas & Electric Company to The Union Gas & Electric Company." September 1, 1906.
      Packet #58) "The People of the State of New York on the relation of the West Side Electric Company v. Consolidated Telegraph and Electrical Subway Company"; New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; record on appeal, volumes I and II; ca. 1905.
      Packet #60) Charles W. Colton v. James I. Raymond (president of A.A. Vantine & Company), et al, including The Manhattan Company; New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; ca. 1900-1906.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 64, 73, 1900-1907 (Offsite-box 35)
      Holds volumes of law office financial records:
      Packet #64) 2 volumes of petty cash books for Delafield, Gould & Longfellow, and later Delafield & Longfellow, January 1900-June 1904; and 1 volume of D&L's stenographer charges for 1908 (in book embossed "lawyer's diary").
      Packet #73) 6 volumes of postage expense records, January 1901-July 1908; and 2 volumes of telegram/telephone expense records, 1901-02, 1905-07.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 65, 72, 79, 1898-1909 (Offsite-box 36)
      This box holds financial records, not print matter:
      Packet #65) Checkstubs for E.P. Delafield, December 1898-October 1899, and lists of deposits to Phenix Bank for EPD, 1899-1901.
      Packet #72) Delafield & Longfellow cancelled checks, 1906-08.
      Packet #79) Volumes of checkstubs: Account opened for Delafield & Gould on 9/19/1895, with stubs to August 1898; then stubs for Delafield, Gould & Longfellow from August 1898-June 1901; then stubs for D&L from June 1901-March 1909.
    - D & L Print Matter Packet 74, 83, 84, circa 1903-1906 (Offsite-box 34)
      Packet #74) Typescript drafts/galleys of indentures involving the Elkhart Electric Company, the New York Security and Trust Company, and the St. Joseph and Elkhart Power Company, ca. 1903-04.
      Packet #83 and 84) Hudson and Manhattan Railroad Company v. Josephine J.S. Wendel; holds typescript drafts/galleys of filings and various related documents, ca. 1905-1906.
    - D & L Print Matter Packets 69, 70, 76, 80, 82, circa 1902-1907 (Offsite-box 33)
      Packet #69) 3 documents: 1) "The Worcester and Connecticut Eastern Railway Company to New York Security and Trust Company (trustee), First mortgage"; October 1, 1902. 2) "Webster and Dudley Street Railway Company to The Worcester and Connecticut Eastern Railway Company, Lease"; September 29, 1902. 3) "Collateral Trust Agreement between Sanderson and Porter and Thompson, Tenney & Crawford and New York Security and Trust Company (trustee)"; re: pledging railway company stock as additional security for above noted mortgage; October 1, 1902.
      Packet #70) "The Hall Signal Company to Empire Trust Company (trustee), First mortgage"; October 10, 1905. Holds typescripts of related documents and drafts of indentures.
      Packet 76) "Indiana and Michigan Electric Company to New York Security and Trust Company (trustee), Second mortgage"; May 24, 1907; and second document with the same title, but date of July 25, 1907. Also for this company a book of temporary receipts for exchange of bonds in connection with a company reorganization, 1907.
      Packet 80) Matter of application and petition of Seth Low, Edward M. Grout, Alexander E. Orr, Charles Stewart Smith, Morris K. Jesup, John H. Starin, Woodbury Langdon, and John Claflin (Board of Rapid Transit Railroad Commissioners of City of New York) in re: acquiring title by the city of lands on westerly side of 4th Avenue, between 8th and 9th streets, in Manhattan re: widening of 4th Avenue. Involves Lewis Delafield as "of counsel" to John Wanamaker and trustees of the Sailors Snug Harbor in City of New York; New York Supreme Court, Special term, Part I; 1907.
      Packet 82) Henry W. Rosenbaum v. Isaac L. Rice, Walter Luttgen, Norman Henderson, George W. Knowlton, John N. Abbott, Consolidated Railway Electric Lighting and Equipment Company, and Consolidated Railway Lighting and Refrigerating Company; New York Supreme Court, New York County, and later New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Dept.; brief for plaintiff, case on appeal; re: breach of duty to corporation; ca. 1903.
- Series II. Boxes labeled LLD (Louis L. Delafield), circa 1858-1909
  The series holds the content of boxes with an original label of "LLD." It is possible that these papers were so labeled because Lewis Delafield II handled the matters, rather than one of his partners, but many of the documents date from the years of Delafield II's partnership with Eugene Hawkins and Robert Sturgis and many of the documents are on the firms' stationery.
  The subseries opens with a set of 12 volumes of case diaries for the date range 1858-1905 for both Lewis Livingston Delafields (I and II). It is possible that some of the earlier files in the series pertain to the legal work of Delafield I, but most is certainly Delafield II. Extensively represented here is legal work for various Delafield family members, as well as affilated families, such as the Wyeths and Primes.
  Other notable matters in this series include: several packets of investigations by Delafield into the solvency of insurance companies seeking to do business in New York State; various claims against the Manhattan Railway Company and Metropolitan Railroad Company; and Delafield's files in relation various reform and bar association matters. Certain matters appear in this series that have many more documents in other series; these include Delafield's work as counsel to Sailors' Snug Harbor in the City of New York and the case of Sarah May Le Brantz v. William G. Conklin, the executor of the will of Sarah Ann Waters.
  The series opens with the set of 12 volumes of case diaries, then turns to the work files, which are the bulk of the content. These documents were originally held in about 60 boxes labeled as LLD, with each label also indicating a number or numbers ranging from 48 to 171, with gaps. Each number represented a packet or packets (the same number was frequently used on multiple packets of documents) in the original box. The container list retains this sequence.
  The LLD boxes are somewhat better organized than the D-L boxes in subseries I.A. Rather than one large bundle per box tied together and holding multiple matters, the LLD boxes tended to have each individual matter set off more clearly, tied in ribbon or in envelopes. For example, at the extreme, LLD packet 132 related to 49 matters, but the boundaries of each is well defined within a numbered envelope.
  As with Subseries I.A., the deteriorated original boxes were all discarded and the contents of each were transferred to plastic enclosures, which were placed in archival record cartons.
  - LLD Legal Case Diaries, 1858-1884 (Offsite-box 164)
    First of two cartons with Delafield I and II's case diaries. This box holds 5 of the 8 volumes. In addition to Delafields, members of the Livingston family are represented most frequently here, especially Robert J. (1811-1891) and his wife Louisa M. (1810-1883).
  - LLD Legal Case Diaries, 1883-1905 (Offsite-box 165)
    Second of two cartons with Delafield I and II's case diaries. This box holds 3 of the 8 volumes. In these later years, the Livingston family largely disappears from the cases. Delafields continue and Prime family appears (LLD II's wife's family). Some cases documented in the collection appear in these volumes, including those concerning the Shipmans and Sailor's Snug Harbor.
  - LLD Packets 48, 49, 50, 51, circa 1878-1907 (Offsite-box 37)
    Packet 48) Rachel Lenox Kennedy will, printed material only, ca. 1897.
    Packet 49) Ethel Thomas v. Harry K. Thaw, ca. 1903-06.
    Packet 50) Matter of Susan Dickie as supposed lunatic, stenographer's transcripts, ca. 1878.
    Packet 51) New York Steam Company v. Foundation Company, ca. 1907.
  - LLD Packets 52, 54, 64, 68, circa 1885-1890 (Offsite-box 37)
    Packet 52) Opinion as to Thomas W. Ludlow dock title, Westchester County/Yonkers, ca. 1887.
    Packet 54) Holds 3 matters: 1) New York City election matters (i.e. separate elections legislation), 1880s. 2) Account of Charlotte W. Prime as general guardian of Charlotte Hoffman Wyeth, a minor, ca. 1885. 3) Account of Maturin L. Delafield as executor of will of Joseph Delafield, ca. 1886.
    Packet 64) People of the State of New York ex el Richard W.G. Welling v. Alexander Meakin et al as Commissioners of Excise, ca. 1890. (This packet was found in a D&L box but was moved here by the N-YHS archivist because it is clearly an LLD matter, as he is Welling's attorney, and the material predates the existence of the D&L firm by about 10 years).
    Packet 68) Annie R. Prime will, 1888. The packet also holds seemingly unrelated documents re: George A. Dingman v. John Mehrtens, ca 1886.
  - LLD Packets 52, 55, 56, 57, 59, 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, circa 1881-1893 (Offsite-box 122)
    (These LLD packets were found in an original box that was incorrectly labeled as Robert Sturgis cases and were redesignated to this LLD series by the processing archivist. Although the archivist corrected a few such obvious errors during the 2022 rehousing, other original misfilings likely remain to some degree.)
    Packet 52) Estate of John Delafield; estate of John Barber Church; French spoliation claims, ca 1885-86.
    Packet 55) Holds 4 matters: 1) Charlotte H. Delafield, draft will & testament, 1886. 2) Annie R. Prime, draft will & testament, 1888. 3) Harriet B. Delafield, draft will & testament, 1884. 4) Lewis L. Delafield (trustee under will of Susan M. Parish) v. Wallace Delafield, ca. 1884.
    Packet 56) Mutual Union Telegraph Company agreement with Alexander Muirhead et al, 1881.
    Packet 57) Holds 2 matters: 1) Emily P. Delafield re: estate of Lewis L. Delafield, ca. 1884. 2) Greenwood Cemetery: Delafield and Parish vaults.
    Packet 59) Lewis L. Delafield, last will & testament, 1883.
    Packet 64) Annie R. Prime (general guardian) v. Charlotte H. Prime, ca. 1886-88.
    Packet 65) Ezra Martin Black, last will & testament, 1892.
    Packet 66) Henry Prime v. Nathaniel Prime, ca. 1886.
    Packet 67) Edgar J. Shipman (guardian of Richard D. Shipman, infant) v. Richard D. Shipman, ca. 1893.
    Packet 68) 2 matters: 1) Leonard J. Wyeth Jr, last will & testament, 1903. 2) John C. Jay v. Mary Rutherford Jay, ca. 1893.
  - LLD Packets 69, 70, 71, 74, circa 1887-1893 (Offsite-box 37)
    Packet 69) 4 matters: 1)Eliza Shipman will, 1892. 2) Marie C. Smith will, 1892. 3) Opinion for Hyde and Jackson as to power of foreign business corporation to condemn lands by eminent domain proceedings in state of Kansas, ca. 1892. 4) Opinion re: Constitutional Convention for New York State, printed matter published by the City Reform Club, 1890s.
    Packet 70) Louise Alley Wyeth estate, ca. 1893.
    Packet 71) Settlement of accounts of executor Edgar J. Shipman for estate of Harriet C. Shipman, and also Edgar's accounts as guardian of Richard D. Shipman (infant), ca. 1887-1889.
    Packet 74) Account of Annie R. Prme as guardian of Charlotte H. Prime (infant), ca. 1888.
  - LLD Packets 77, 79, 81, 83, circa 1894-1896 (Offsite-box 38)
    Packet 77) J.H. Myers, opinion on American Ballot Machine Company, re: voting methods, ca. 1894.
    Packet 79) Elizabeth H. Merchant v. Stephen L. Merchant et al, re: estate of Frederick H. Wolcott, ca. 1895.
    Packet 81) John D. Crimmins v. John J. Amory et al, ca. 1896.
    Packet 83) Accounts of Edgar J. Shipman as guardian of Richard H. Shipman (infant), ca. 1895.
  - LLD Packets 85, 87, 89, 91, 92, circa 1880-1898 (Offsite-box 38)
    Packet 85) Francis J. Kennett v. George B. Hopkins and Harry L. Terry (LLD is referee), ca. 1896.
    Packet 87) Frederick Prime will and codicils, 1880.
    Packet 89) Benjamin H. Irving (executor) v. Jane R. Irving et al re: Mary Irving estate, ca. 1897.
    Packet 91) Nathalie E. Baylies v. Schuyler Van Cortlandt Hamilton et al and Alexandra Schuyler Hamilton, printed material only, 1898.
    Packet 92) Richard D. Shipman (infant) by Lewis L. Delafield, (guardian) v. Albert Delafield et al, ca. 1898.
  - LLD Packets 93, 94, 95, circa 1895-1898 (Offsite-box 39)
    Packet 93) Holds 2 matters: 1) Henry C. Eno and William P. Eno as executors of Amos R. Eno estate v. Amos F. Eno, et al, and related matters, ca. 1898. 2) Settlement of account of Albert Delafield, administrator for estate of Susan P. Delafield, ca. 1898.
    Packet 94) Holds 2 matters: 1) Settlement of account of executors of Harriet B. Delafield estate, ca. 1897. 2) Albert Delafield et al as executor of estate of Richard Delafield v. Edgar J. Shipman et al, ca. 1895.
    Packet 95) Petition of Theodore E. Hancock (New York State Attorney General) to bring action to annul the Charter of the City Gas Company of New York, ca. 1898; and related petition of Francis B. Thurber and William McCarroll to Hancock.
  - LLD Packets 97, 100, 101, 103, 104, circa 1899-1904 (Offsite-box 39)
    Packet 97) Lucy W. Rollins will, 1899.
    Packet 100) Arbitration between Luther D. Garrett and London and Lancashire Fire Insurance Company, ca. 1904.
    Packet 101) Application of Amalia Martinez Ybor de Garcia Velez for order directing the New York City Chamberlain to pay over monies, ca. 1901.
    Packet 103) Holds 3 matters: 1) Richard D. Shipman will, ca 1900. 2) Eva Wyeth will, ca. 1901. 3) Alfred J. Cipriant estate.
    Packet 104) Holds 4 matters: 1) Howard Duffield will, ca. 1901. 2) Luther D. Garrett and London and Lancashire Fire Insurance Company matter, ca. 1900. 3) Application of Edgar J. Shipman as guardian for an order authorizing sale of stock, ca. 1901. 4) L.D. Garrett Company agreements with Traders Fire Insurance Company, ca. 1900.
  - LLD Packets 105, 106, circa 1899-1900 (Offsite-box 39)
    Packet 105) Holds 3 matters: 1) Marion Sturgis will. 2) Richard D. Shipman v. Albert Delafield. 3) Russell Sturgis estate. All ca. 1899-1900.
    Packet 106) James B. Colgate et al v. Augusta B. Greene, ca. 1900.
  - LLD Packets 107, 108, 109, 110, 111, circa 1897-1907 (Offsite-box 40)
    Packet 107) Holds 2 matters: 1) Annie R. Prime as guardian of Charlotte H. Prime v. Markus Guttman, et al re: mortgage foreclosure, ca. 1897. Other papers in this packet too: E.H. Rollins & Sons (corporation) v. Trowbridge, MacDonald & Niver Company, et al, ca 1899; and Emily P. Delafield agreements with Adelheit and Frederick Neimeir, ca. 1886. 2) Mercantile Trust Company and Allen Zollars (trustee) v. Findlay, Fort Wayne & Western Railway Company, US District Court, Northern District of Ohio, ca. 1902.
    Packet 108) Emma Gray Hamilton will, ca. 1902.
    Packet 109) Holds 3 matters: 1) George Kennedy Smith will, ca. 1899. 2)People on the complaint of Thomas J. Maguire v. Robert McLellan, ca. 1902. 3) Agreement between Margaret O.F. Bronson with Thomas E. Jevons re: Huntington, LI title, ca. 1901.
    Packet 110) Nathan Ries to Leslie Coffman mortgage, ca. 1907.
    Packet 111) Documents re: increase of capital stock for the Century Bank of New York, ca. 1907. Also includes related documents for the Corn Exchange Bank.
    Packet 115) Henry W. Rosenbaum v. Isaac L. Rice et al, ca. 1901.
  - LLD Packet 117 (and 101) (Offsite-box 40)
    Packet 117) Matthew Byrnes estate re: application of United States Mortgage & Trust Company to sell real estate from the Byrnes estate, ca. 1901. The box with packet 117 also held a second packet numbered 101 that relates to 117 and so was left here.
  - LLD Packet 121, circa 1900-1906 (Offsite-box 41)
    Holds 3 matters:
    1) Settlement of account of John Fiske re: Mary Fiske Stoughton, an incompetent person, ca. 1900.
    2) Various documents concerning matter re: investigation of ballots under Section 114 of New York Election Law, ca. 1905-06 re: William Travers Jerome candidacy for Attorney General. Includes The People of the State of New York on the relation of William Randolph Hearst v. Board of County Canvassers of New York County re: void and protested ballots in the 1st and 6th assembly districts.